

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211





Hemant Rac Hemant Rao @ Featured |] Senior Manager with 17 years of experience in Cloud and Infrastructure domain as Presales consultant, Digital transformation advisor, Transformation Management, Business development and Strategic planning of IT services Total Experience: 17 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Designation: Senior Manager Current Company: Mphasis Ltd. Notice Period: 2 Months Highest Degree: MBAPGDM [Project Management] Current Location: Pune Pref. Location: Pune, Hyderabad, Bengaluru / Bangalore Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Maintenance Role: Program Mar Industry: IT-Software/Software Services Marital Status: Married Key Skills: Presales Consultant, Cloud & Infrastructure Transformation, Program Management, Practice Management, Delivery Management, Risk Management, Vendor Management, P&L Management, Digital Transformation Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Jump to Section

Last Active: 19-Jan-21

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Summary

Technology driven solution-oriented IT professional with 16+ Years of total experience having played multiple roles in architecture (Cloud & Data center) and management (Infrastructure & Digital Transformation)

Core expertise involves Practice development, Presales for cloud & infrastructure services for multiyear managed projects, techno function audits of delivery accounts, creating pipeline within existing account via account mining/scope reviews etc. Possess exhaustive experience in IT Strategy & Governance, developing differentiators and collaterals, Go To Market strategy, Risk Management, Service design, P&L & cost management and program management. Strong Business Development skills in customer facing capacity involving 30% travel to international locations such as UK & USA Major verticals my experience caters to are: Banking & Finance, Insurance, Pharmaceutical, Manufacturing & Retail, Airline Transportation.

Work Experience

Mphasis Ltd. as Senior Manager Apr 2008 to Till Date

Grew practice by 65% in revenue and 18% in headcount Won 2 large transformation & managed mode (\$110+ mil USD) deals Worked on consultant lead composite deals worth 150+ mil Converted 7 T&Mprojects into Managed mode service delivery

Helped increase overall practice margin by 5% yearly

Planned and initiated 4 transformation projects (on-prem to cloud migration, datacenter relocation, datacenter migration & database migration)

Delivered solutions for digital transformation, cloud adaption, Data Center infrastructure consolidation, Disaster Recovery, Database upgrade/migration/transformation and Mddleware support for variety of high-end products. Responsible for Cloud Infrastructure Pre-Sales, Solution Design, Market research & Competition analysis. Built solution around laaS, PaaS, SaaS, Hybrid, Converged & Hyper converged as well as legacy services Conceptualizes and program manages the solution design and facilitates integration of services across Applications (primarily), Infrastructure, and Business Processes

Built practice collaterals, sales pitch presentations, perform due-diligence, identify gaps and business opportunities to engage with client in consultative solutioning. Conduct presentations, lead RFP, RFI, Orals as solution architect. Worked with OEM to define Go To Market strategy, build new service offerings & revenue channel for business unit. Integrated proposal contents after collating responses from all stakeholders; included graphics, call-out texts; proof-read, standardized, and performed quality checks to make the proposal - a winning proposal

Responsible for client presentations, act as a bridge between Sales and Technical Delivery teams during proposal phase, support Sales and Global Account Delivery Leaders (SaGDAL) with technical strategy definition and development of technical relationships with-in existing accounts as well as at new customers

Created right POCs, POVs and proposals to help win new clients and grow our work with existing clients. Maintained a deep understanding of analytics technology landscape including trends, key platform vendors etc. Contribute with technical & architecture guidance, for various technology areas in the Data & Al spectrum. Collaborate with account and sales teams to lead the pre-sales process with clients and provide the technology leadership throughout the opportunity lifecycle.

Hold a key role in Presales Solution in pursuing and winning large multi-tower outsourcing deals in the 100-150MUSD TCV range by defining the overall solution strategy to effectively address client needs and provide differentiation



Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld t e vitalige by delitiling the evelan conductionationy to encouvery address districted and provide anterentation

As Presales Solution Lead drive the business and technology transformation strategy for the client.

Executes pricing strategies (Price to Win, Rate to Win, etc.)

Defines the overall solution strategy to effectively address client needs and provide differentiation (including ownership of the Business Value Articulation)

Supports Pursuit Lead to develop the winning proposition

Architects the overall solution approach (including pricing), Executes pricing strategies (Price to Win, Rate to Win, etc.) Reviews and Owns Solution content along with commercial and legal terms that might impact the solution.

Delivered projects of 40+ mil (5 years) with above average margin and profitability.

80% of my projects got renewed/extend after end of SoW.

Planned & implemented SaaS based SDP

Transformed legacy service delivery to point based delivery across various client business units

Converted RED to GREEN - Database & middleware being critical part of operations team, converted a few red projects to green and supporting them till end of SOW.

Established the process from scratch: Successfully lead the IT operations of a virtually-integrated team that was commissioned at multiple delivery locations globally and was operating in different time-shifts.

Synechron Technologies as Database Lead

Mar 2007 to Apr 2008

(Accomplishment - Developed & rolled out TENS/PPES management model)

Maximize Technologies as Database Specialist

Feb 2006 to Mar 2007

(Accomplishment - Implemented multi-site data replication with conflict resolvers)

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: Bachelors in IT (Information Systems and Multimedia) from Indira Gandhi National Open University (IGNOU) in 2003

PG: MBA/PGDM (Project Management) from Sikkim Manipal University (SMU) in 2012

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
AWS, Azure, OCI, GitHub, Azure			
Jenkins, Ansible, Chef, Puppet, QlikView			
Windows, RHEL, SuSe, AIX, MySQL,			
MS Project, MS Visio, Active Directory			
Apache, Kafka, Tomcat, IIS, JBoss			

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent/Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.